[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
[Emilia] Dead people belong to this grave.
And you are dead.
Where did that come from?!
I don't want to see that!
Get that away from me!
Do you realize the mess
you're getting into?
I'm not scared,
because I know someone powerful.
More powerful than that politician
you're protecting!
[Julio] Who else dared to go against me?
Lily Cruz.
I want you to hunt down Lily Cruz.
I want her dead. Do you understand me?
[Jepoy] If your life was in danger before,
then it's even more so now.
What are you going to do now?
Jump off this cliff?
Or would you rather get shot?
[man] No one could survive
falling from that height!
[Julio] Don't forget the people
who did this to you.
Use that hate so that you may rise
and rule by my side once again.
[Camia] How did your meeting go?
[Diego] I am hoping that the
vice governor won't let us down.
Don't worry, Aunt Camia.
I'll do whatever it takes
to finish Lily's fight.
We can do this.
[man] This is from the governor.
[Leandro] Tell Governor Ardiente
that I'm looking forward
to his celebration.
[Julio] Citizens of Ardiente!
We invite all of you
to join us in the celebration
of our province's one-hundredth year!
[crowd cheering]
-[festive music playing]
-[man] Viva Ardiente!
[festive music playing]
[man] Viva Ardiente!
[festive music continues]
HAPPY CENTENNIAL ANNIVERSARY,
POBLACION ARDIENTE!
Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
Viva Ardiente!
[woman] Long live, Ardiente!
[marching band playing]
[crowd] Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
They will still bow down to the king.
[tense music playing]
I still have Poblacion Ardiente
wrapped around my finger.
[tense music playing]
[woman 1] Viva! Viva Ardiente!
[woman 2] Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
[crowd] Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
[woman squealing]
[crowd chanting] Viva Ardiente!
Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
[Julio] Hi!
-[woman 3] Happy fiesta!
-[Julio] Thank you!
[music swells]
Remember, we're attending the celebration
not to cause trouble or to protest.
We're still citizens
of Poblacion Ardiente.
We have the right to join in
the festivities of our province.
-Right!
-[all] That's right!
-All right!
-[Camia] Right, Loring?
That's right So let's go.
-Let's go.
-Yes.
-[Camia] All right.
-[Loring] Come on.
Um…
Can't you just stay behind?
Why, Damian?
You might get into trouble out there.
No, I won't.
[inhales sharply]
Camia, in case you've forgotten,
you're the only one left in your family.
Damian, if Dante were still alive,
he'd go there too.
And that's the reason he
and your daughter are gone now.
I'm ready to lay down my life
for the people of Poblacion Ardiente.
That's what Lily believed in
and that's what I believe in too.
But are they ready to do the same for you?
-That's not important anymore.
-To you, it's not.
[sighs] But to me, it is.
Dante's greatest mistake was forgetting
his responsibilities to you
as your husband.
It was his responsibility
to take care of you and Lily,
not to give justice to other people.
But I chose this.
That's what you think, Camia,
because you feel that no one's
taking care of you.
-And that's--
-Damian…
Dante loved me.
But not in the way you deserve.
What do you mean by that?
Nothing.
[sighs] Nothing.
All right.
Just be careful out there.
[somber music playing]
Commissioner, someone
wants to talk with you.
Didn't I tell you to cancel
all my appointments?
I'm going to Poblacion Ardiente, remember?
-He says it's urgent.
-Commissioner, we need to talk.
Mr. Torillo, I rejected your appeal
because it lacks evidence.
If I were you, I'd just accept defeat.
Commissioner, I didn't come here for that.
[tense music playing]
Then what?
[ominous music playing]
I'm sorry, but you
aren't allowed to enter.
-What?
-Why not?
We live in Poblacion Ardiente.
We are residents of this town too.
I'm sorry, but you're not on the list.
What list? This one?
You haven't even checked it yet.
How'd you know we're not on it?
[Julio] Excuse me, excuse me. Hold on.
You are not allowed
to enter here, because…
You're not. [chuckles]
Your attire does not fit
the motif of the party.
But we're residents
of Poblacion Ardiente too.
-[man 1] That's right.
-Oh. I got news for you, girl.
Not for long. Not for long.
Sanggano, if these people
insist on coming in,
-feel free to arrest them.
-Yes, Governor.
-[man 2] This old man!
-I love to be in power.
-Not for long?
-We dressed up for nothing.
We'll see about that.
[tense music playing]
[host] Let's all give
a warm round of applause
for the Ardiente family!
[crowd applauding, cheering]
[marching band playing]
[crowd chanting]
Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente!
Viva Ardiente!
[music fading]
Governor, the area is secure.
Okay. I just got word
that Secretary Martel
is near Ardiente already.
So I want you to ready our men
and meet him at the arch.
He's your number one priority
as far as security is concerned.
Convoy him on the way here.
-Yes, Governor.
-Okay.
[host] Good evening, everyone.
Let us begin our grand celebration.
And for the opening remarks,
let us give a round of applause
for our former governor.
Our one and only best friend…
Mrs. Emilia Ardiente-Torillo!
-[crowd applauding]
-[marching band playing]
Hello, friends!
And to everyone,
a warm welcome to you all!
This night is a very special one
because it is the celebration
of our province's centennial!
Congratulations to us.
-Viva Ardiente!
-[crowd applauding]
-[crowd] Viva Ardiente!
-[applauding]
But this isn't just
a celebration of our town.
It is also a celebration
of the return of someone
very dear to my heart and yours too.
Someone who gave his life,
his time,
and his whole heart for our province.
The one you all chose to lead our people.
Let us give a round of applause
for my father,
Governor Julio Ardiente!
[crowd applauding, cheering]
Papa, we have a surprise for you
and for everyone here tonight.
Let us all welcome,
the talented Ardiente Dancers!
-[applauding]
-[metal drums clanging]
[chiming musically]
[tribal music continues]
[ominous music playing]
[music stops]
[upbeat tribal music playing]
[ominous music playing]
Ma'am, someone asked me to give you this.
-Huh? From who?
-This is for you.
They didn't say.
[crowd applauding]
-[phone ringing]
-[suspenseful music playing]
[Emilia] Aren't you glad
I left that little cell phone
inside that casket?
And you have me for company.
[phone continues ringing]
[host] Let's give the Ardiente Dancers
a round of applause!
-[crowd applauding]
-[phone continues ringing]
[host] And now, I'd like to call
on our vice governor
to recognize the honorable
citizens of Ardiente.
-[crowd applauding]
-[suspenseful music playing]
[phone continues ringing]
-[phone continues ringing]
-No.
[phone continues ringing]
No… This can't be happening.
-[phone continues ringing]
-No.
[phone continues ringing]
Hello?
Hello, Emilia.
[suspenseful music playing]
No… This is impossible.
This is not happening.
Was it really impossible
to hear from me again, Emilia?
Yes, because I heard
your last breath, Ivy!
You're dead!
You're right, Emilia. Ivy Aguas is dead.
No…
This is not happ-- No.
[gasps]
How--
[breathing heavily]
Emilia?
Oh.
Raul.
Are you okay? What are you doing here?
[voice shaking] Nothing.
Just getting some fresh air.
[tense music playing]
Okay. Let's go?
We would like to thank
Vice Governor Mateo Ruiz,
and the veterans of Poblacion Ardiente.
Let's give them a round of applause!
[crowd cheering, applauding]
And now, I know everyone's
excited to hear his message.
Without further ado,
let's call on our province's
beloved father.
Give it up for Governor Julio Ardiente!
-[march band playing]
-[crowd cheering, applauding]
[crowd] Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
-Thank you very much, everyone.
-[camera shutters clicking]
Fellow citizens of Ardiente,
it's so heartwarming to see your
overwhelming love and support
for this humble servant.
I know none of this would've
been possible…
without your trust in me.
So, in return,
I will promise you one thing…
If anyone dares to take
this province for themselves…
Or you, my children, for that matter…
I will make sure that they answer to me.
[crowd cheering, applauding]
-[crowd] Viva Ardiente!
-[Julio] Viva Ardiente!
I will not allow anyone
to waltz into this province
and take my family away from me.
The reason we won over our rivals
is that we're united as one family.
[crowd applauding]
And if ever my enemies and detractors
accuse me of doing things
I've never committed,
I will not be fazed.
Because the truth will always,
without a doubt, prevail!
[crowd cheering, applauding]
[tense music playing]
Viva Ardiente!
[all] Viva Ardiente!
[lights flick]
-[crowd exclaiming]
-[Julio] What happened?
[crowd exclaiming]
What's going on?
What?
[ominous music playing]
[ominous music continues]
Lilies?
[foreboding music playing]
[indistinct shouting]
[suspenseful music playing]
[smoke hissing]
[smoke hissing continues]
[suspenseful music playing]
[epic action music playing]
[woman 1] Ivy! It's Ivy!
[indistinct crowd chatter]
[epic action music playing]
[explodes]
[crowd exclaiming]
[epic action music continues]
[explodes]
[tense music playing]
[inaudible]
You're not real.
Because you're dead, Ivy Aguas!
You're dead!
Yes, Ivy Aguas is dead.
Ivy Aguas is dead.
But Lily Cruz…
[ominous music playing]
…is very much alive!
[man 1] Lily Cruz? How did that happen?
-[woman 2] Isn't she dead?
-[man 2] Lily Cruz is alive?
[crowd chatter indistinctly]
Lily Cruz isn't dead.
I am Lily Cruz.
-[tense music playing]
-[crowd gasping]
I am the real Lily Cruz!
And this time, you Ardientes
will be the ones this town will mourn for.
And starting tonight, at this very moment,
you will finally lose all your power!
Others may cry for you, but not me.
I will never, ever shed a tear.
That's why I'm not wearing black.
'Cause black is out!
Gold is in!
Yes, just like gold, I am indestructible!
[epic action music playing]
[epic action music continues]
[clock ticking]
[gasping]
[coughs, gasps]
[panting]
Ivy, hold on!
[screams]
[somber music playing]
[water trickling in distance]
[grunting]
[water trickling]
[suspenseful music playing]
-[thumps]
-[grunts]
-[grunting]
-[thumping]
[suspenseful music playing]
[wood breaking]
[water trickling in distance]
[Lily coughing]
[coughing continues]
[gunshots]
[henchman] After them!
[Lily coughing, gasping]
Lily!
[groaning]
[ominous music playing]
Lily… Lily, wake up!
-Lily, wake up!
-[groaning]
Lily!
[Marlon] Be on the lookout!
You, check that area!
[somber music playing]
Ivy?
Diego! Jepoy!
Ivy's over here!
Jepoy, Diego… Marlon's calling!
-[Jepoy] What?
-He found Ivy!
[suspenseful music playing]
[Julio] You're too late.
You're too late, Ivy Aguas--
or Lily Cruz, whoever you are.
Dead or alive, you're too late.
Because I've been declared
governor of Ardiente!
I am Julio Ardiente…
and this is my province.
Martel! I'm glad you could make it.
Tell everyone here who the real king of--
[Diego] Julio Ardiente!
[tense music playing]
I believe this is your money.
The money you used
to bribe Secretary Martel!
-[crowd murmuring]
-[tense music playing]
You're fighting a losing battle,
Julio Ardiente.
This is justice served
by the hand of Lily Cruz.
[tense music playing]
This is justice for Poblacion Ardiente!
[woman 4] Goodness.
[Lily] No matter how high you've
exalted yourself,
I, Lily Cruz,
will drag you down
to where you truly belong!
[suspenseful music playing]
[police] Governor Julio Ardiente,
we have a warrant for your arrest
for the attempted murder of Camia Cruz.
[suspenseful music continues]
What?
[inaudible]
You can't do this to me!
I am Julio Ardiente!
I suggest you come with us, sir.
-No… No!
-Don't touch me!
[tense music playing]
Why don't you arrest this fraud instead--
[foreboding music playing]
[thuds]
Papa!
[suspenseful music playing]
[cracks]
-[crowd exclaiming]
-[bodyguard 1] Sir…
[Emilia] Papa!
Papa!
[Lily] You've lost, Julio Ardiente.
[in Spanish] Farewell, Grandpa!
Call our lawyers! [gasps] Call our--
Papa!
How dare you! Papa!
That's enough. Come on. Let's go. Get up.
[Emilia] Papa!
[Raul] Let's go.
[bodyguard 2] Hey, hey! Sir… Sir! Sir!
Let's bring him to the hospital!
[bodyguard 3] Governor! Governor!
-Make way! Make way!
-Let's go!
We aren't done yet!
Cower in fear, Emilia,
because Lily Cruz has returned!
[suspenseful music playing]
-[Emilia] Arnaldo!
-[Raul] Arnaldo!
-[crowd exclaiming]
[Raul] Arnaldo! Call a doctor!
Call an ambulance!
[Raul] Arnaldo, son! Call a doctor!
[clamoring]
[Emilia] Help us…
[suspenseful music playing]
[music fading]
[Emilia] Arnaldo!
[Julio] Why isn't anyone listening to me?!
-I'm okay!
-Help them!
-I'm fine!
-[Emilia] Doctor! Hurry up!
You should look at my grandson
instead, please.
-Let me get out of here.
-[Emilia] Please help Arnaldo!
I'm starting to sound
like a broken record here!
-My son…
-I'm okay!
-Get me out of here! Come on!
-[doctor 1] Julio…
I suggest that we do some tests
so we know the cause of your chest pains.
My chest hurts because
of that blasted Lily Cruz.
-[Emilia] What's happening?!
-[Julio] Because of her lies!
-Emilia, please…
-Doctor!
Julio, you have to…
-[Emilia shrieking]
-You have to calm down, Julio.
Get his blood pressure.
-[Emilia] Nurse!
-[doctor 2] Nurse!
-[Emilia] Nurse, come here!
-Emilia!
-[doctor 1] You have to calm down.
-Get me Diazepam, one ampoule. Go!
Faster!
Doctor!
Arnaldo! Papa?
Papa! Is he okay, doctor?
He's going to be all right.
He's gonna be okay.
Papa, wait, okay? Wait.
Raul, don't just stand there!
If you don't do anything,
I'll have you wake up
in a hospital bed as well!
Doctor, what is happening?! Come on!
Arnaldo, son, please.
[exhales sharply] Is he gonna be okay now?
Your son is going to be okay.
We just need to run some tests
to find the cause of the seizure.
-He's going to be fine.
-[Raul] Thank you, doctor.
[doctor 2] He's going to be fine.
[somber music playing]
[sobbing]
[nurse] Please make way.
[somber music continues]
Let's just wait for
the ombudsman's notification.
Julio can still post bail,
but we are gunning
for his indefinite suspension as governor.
And if he's proven guilty,
then he'll be banned from public office.
So if that happens, he can't run
for any position in government,
be it district chairman
or president of the Philippines?
Attorney, Vice Governor,
auntie, friends…
thank you for all your help.
And, of course, thank you, Ivy.
The Ardientes wouldn't have
fallen if it weren't for you.
We've finally taken back what's ours.
We know that the Ardientes
are formidable enemies.
But because we worked together
and didn't give up,
those monsters no longer have their power.
So thank you very much for all your help.
I promise you, I will help
the citizens of Ardiente
with the position you entrusted me.
For a new Ardiente.
[reflective music playing]
Doctor, how is my son?
Arnaldo is stable.
The seizure was caused
by an insufficient dosage
of his medication.
This was indicated in
the results of his blood test.
We will have to impose necessary steps
to prevent this from happening again.
What about Papa, doctor? How is he?
Unfortunately, he's still unconscious.
But he's stable.
We just have to give him
more time to recover.
But he's okay.
[inaudible]
[somber music playing]
[sobbing]
Papa…
[Emilia sobbing]
Papa, wake up.
Come on, you've got to wake up, Papa.
[sobs]
You have to wake up.
You can't leave me yet, Papa.
Papa, I know you.
I know you're a fighter.
When you wake up,
and I know you will…
because you'll force yourself to wake up.
Come on. Wake up, Papa…
[sobbing] Wake up!
You can't die, Papa.
You're an Ardiente.
Weren't you the one who said
you'll live forever?
So you can't die.
I know you, Papa.
I know you won't let
a nobody like Lily Cruz
tarnish and ruin our family's reputation.
That's why you can't die on me, Papa!
[sobbing]
Please, Papa…
[melancholic music playing]
[sobbing]
Let's go.
[pensive music playing]
-Mom, what happened to you?
-[shushing]
-Hey!
-[gasps]
Lily! Run!
[tires screeching]
My mom?
My mom is alive.
Mom?
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
The Ardientes have broken us
again and again.
Now, it's our turn to be whole
while they fall apart.
Our family will be whole again, Mom.
And we will never be broken again.
[pensive music playing]
I'm sure Lily's happy now
that the Ardientes have fallen
and we have a new governor.
I'm so happy for all of us.
Diego, thank you so much.
But still, Camia, don't let
your guard down.
[sighs]
["Wildflower" instrumental playing]
All right. Auntie, Diego,
I'm going upstairs.
-Me too.
-All right. Good night, you two.
Oh, Lily.
Lily, dear.
I thought you went home.
["Wildflower" instrumental swells]
["Wildflower" instrumental playing]
["Wildflower" instrumental continues]
[sobs]
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda playing]
♪ Let her cry ♪
♪ For she's a lady… ♪
-The governor's conscious now.
-Thank you, doctor.
He's undergone oxygen therapy.
I also prescribed some medication
to prevent blood clotting,
and to improve the blood flow
through the arteries.
-[sighs] Thank you.
-He's going to be okay.
Thanks, doctor.
You're welcome.
[somber music playing]
[sighs]
[sobbing]
Lily, I'll just fix my room.
You can sleep there for the night.
[inhales sharply]
Mom…
I don't want to sleep here
just for tonight.
[voice shaking] If it's all right…
I want to stay here for good.
I want to live with you, Mom.
Oh, Lily…
I never thought this day would come.
[soft piano music playing]
But it's finally here.
It's finally come, Mom.
This is it.
After everything we've been through,
this day has finally come for us,
we can now live together…
because I'm finally free.
Ivy Aguas is dead
and Lily Cruz is free again.
Everyone knows that I'm Lily Cruz.
We can finally live
under one roof again, Mom.
I can be with my mother again.
Yes, dear, now that we've won…
embrace your victory.
Hold it tight.
Mom, this is my victory…
To finally be with you.
The two of us together,
along with everyone I love.
This is my greatest victory, Mom.
Mom.
[soft piano music playing]
Papa.
Get me out of here, Emilia.
Relax.
The doctor said you're going
to be discharged tomorrow.
And Attorney De Jesus called.
He said he's taking care of your case
so you can post bail.
Aren't you glad?
Glad?
How can I be glad…
knowing that the vermin
who caused the downfall
of our family is still alive
and roaming freely out there?
That damn Lily Cruz…
Neither Ivy Aguas
nor Lily Cruz--
or whatever name she's using--
will bring me down.
Does she actually think she's smart?
Her followers are nothing but simpletons
who believe whatever a populist says.
[scoffs]
They will never bring me down.
Not them.
So, do they think that their lives
are gonna be better
in the hands of those amateurs?
Damn. Just wait and see.
Once I get out of this hospital
and post my bail,
I will take back my rightful place.
But, Papa, you shot Camia Cruz.
So what?
If I see that woman again,
I'll shoot her again.
Papa, you can post your bail,
but you can't return
to being a governor again.
Papa, you're so doomed.
You are so doomed.
[tense music playing]
From this day forward, you will address me
by my real name,
Lily Cruz.
What's more important to you?
Becoming the queen of Ardiente,
or discovering your mom's identity?
Both. I want to be the queen of Ardiente
and have acting Governor Mateo Ruiz
at my beck and call.
[screams]
-Someone wants to see you.
-Who?
Red Dragon.
[tense music playing]
[theme music playing]